Paul MIETZ EGLI

721 Fair Ave. Santa Cruz, CA 95060

mobile 831 902 0434 email paul@obscure.com

PROFILE

Web and mobile applications expert with ten years of experience designing scalable, secure products that serve millions of end users. Collaborative developer who focuses on results over process and getting things done right. Proven record of delivering products on time.

EXPERIENCE

Principal Applications Architect, Fullpower Technologies, Inc. June 2006 - present

Hands-on architect responsible for the design, development, and deployment of server infrastructure for applications which showcase Fullpower's sensor technology platform on mobile devices. Part of the team which deployed the top selling MotionX-GPS and MotionX-GPS Drive applications for the iPhone. Designed and implemented server-side tracking of in-app purchases and fulfillment using the Apple App Store. Created services for GPS track and waypoint sharing, import/export, application diagnostics and support systems. Manage and deploy production servers and infrastructure.

Mobile Application Developer, ThelceBreak.com July 2011 - March 2012

Contracted to build a mobile application for ThelceBreak.com, a website focused on building personal relationships. App was built using Appcelerator Titanium and included integration with back-end servers for authentication, data posting and retrieval, and photo uploading.

Mobile Application Developer, AppSmitten.com March 2012 - September 2012

Contracted to build a mobile application for AppSmitten.com which provided app recommendations and social sharing features. The app was built with Titanium and featured several custom UI components which I later released as open source.

Server Engineer, LightSurf Technologies, Inc. Engineer IV, VeriSign January 2000 - June 2006

Senior server software developer responsible for design of vertical application APIs and services, development of new technologies, and incorporation of these technologies into the company's web-based and multimedia messaging products. Responsible for research, design, and development of the company's core codebase. Investigated, evaluated, and championed new technologies that have improved the company's ability to deliver to multiple customers. Implemented consumer photo-sharing web sites for corporate customers such as Motorola, Sprint, mmO2, and Kodak. Designed and implemented services and protocols for integration with customer and third-party systems for billing, account migration, single sign-on and authentication, MMSCs, and SMSCs. Designed a protocol for wireless media upload and management. Implemented a server that featured pluggable extension of the protocol and worked with firmware engineers to support the device-based client library.

Paul MIETZ EGLI

EXPERIENCE, CONTINUED

Group Leader, Scientific Information Technology Group, Affymax Research Institute November 1996 - February 2000

Technology lead of the scientific applications development group at Affymax, a research center of Glaxo-Wellcome plc. Designed and implemented the data models for storing corporate biological information critical to drug discovery efforts. Developed unique software solutions critical to all areas of research, including the industry's first web-based chemical ordering and inventory system

Instructor - Computers, Technology, and Information Systems, Foothill-DeAnza Community College June 1999 - March 2000

Part-time instructor for evening classes at the Foothill campus. Taught Intermediate HTML, Web Server Administration, and substituted for CGI Programming in Perl and UNIX System Administration.

earlier work experience available upon request

OPEN SOURCE

- Contributor to several open source projects, including TouchDB and Appcelerator products.
- Provided several open-source extensions to Appcelerator Titanium, including a wrapper for TouchDB and several custom UI extensions.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science, Microbiology - University of California, Davis - 1989

SKILLS

- Extensive experience in all aspects of web application development, including client UI, remoting, server API design
 and implementation, and data persistence.
- Expert Java programmer, primarily focused on J2EE and server-side technologies including OSGi and application servers with practical implementation experience in various J2ME platforms.
- Developed and deployed both relational and non-relational storage systems on various platforms, including Oracle (database, PL/SQL, and C API), MySQL, PostgreSQL (including PostGIS), and CouchDb.
- Created moderate and complex mobile applications for iOS using Objective-C.
- Ten years of research work in biotechnology with a special emphasis on statistical information analysis and experimental design. Published in peer-reviewed journals and invited speaker at professional conferences.

OTHER INTERESTS

California Repercussions

Perform and travel with a group of Bay Area musicians, playing gigs including the Northern California Small Brewers Festival, the Sacramento Jazz Festival, and Oktoberfest in Munich.

The Rabbit Haven

Provide foster care and volunteer work for the Santa Cruz County animal shelter and a local house rabbit rescue group.

other recent activities include kayaking, roller hockey, road cycling, and triathlon.